

# **Arnab Mondal**

MS | IIT KGP || Software Eng. | LISTER || BE | IIESTS

- August 23, 1992
- Keshiary, West Bengal, India 721133
- +91.7358367285 (Whatsapp) / 8167808059
- ttps://arnab-m.github.io
- @ amondal23@iitkgp.ac.in

### About Me -

I'm an exceptionally energetic, precise and result situated analyst cum software engineer with technical experience in the domain of Cyber-physical Systems (CPS), Internet of Things (IoT), and Software Development. I love working in a team since it helps to learn and grow much faster. As I like the saying: 'Talent wins games, but teamwork and intelligence win championships'.

### Profiles -



LinkedIn

Google Scholar

### Soft Skills -



### **Working Experience**

Jun 2017 – Mar 2021

# Hardware Software Co-design and CAD design As Research Consultant

SRIC, IIT Kharagpur

# Developed a programmable testbed with open architecture for scheduling and analysis of Multi-hop Control Networks in CPS.

# Created a software tool using AngularJS, Python, and Open-modelica for automated generation of smart micro power grid design. [Github Repo]

2018 – 2020

#### Experimental demonstration of wireless CPS As Teaching Assistant

CSE, IIT Kharagpur

IIT Kharagnur

# Demonstrated of a distributed embedded system, where multiple sensor nodes exchanged control signals over a wireless network.

# Mentored a couple of students' group in the course term projects "Delay-Aware Real-Time Wireless Networked Control System" and "Securing Real-time Multi-hop Wireless Networked Control System". [Course Webpage]

Sep 2015 – May 2017

# **End-to-end Web Development**As **Software Engineer**

Lister Technologies P Ltd, Chennai

# Responsible for Extended Promotion features, Third-party integrations (e.g. Google Map, Oracle Responsys etc.), Shopping Cart development, Extended Checkout flow, Extended Order management, Order Export flow development, MyAccount development and implementing Flexible Design for eight countries websites both Desktop and Mobile that offer to learn of more than 30 languages. [https://www.rosettastone.com]

# Developed fast and powerful web interfaces using UIkit, a lightweight and modular front-end framework.

# Worked on BigCommerce, Webhooks and Management APIs.

# Worked with Salesforce, a customer relationship management solution, and ContexTip's Recommendation engine that uses data that lives in Salesforce.

#### **Education**

lan 2018 -

ongoing	CGPA/Marks: 7.11/10; Focus: Wireless Cyber-physical	Systems.
Jun 2011 – May 2015	Bachelor of Engineering CGPA/Marks: 8.02/10; Focus: Electrical Engineering.	IIEST Shibpur
May 2008 – May 2010	<b>Higher Secondary – 12th</b> Midnapore Collegiate Sch CGPA/Marks: 87.6%; Focus: Mathematics, Physics, and and Computer science.	
Jun 2005 – April 2008	Madhyamik - 10th  CGPA/Marks: 93.5%; Focus: Physical science, Mathe science, and Arts.	

MS by Posparch (Supervisor: Dr Soumvaiit Day)

#### Awards and Achievements

Awaius	and Acmevements	
2011	GEN Rank 555 (Top 0.5 percent) out of approx. 1,30,000 candidates.	int Entrance Exam (WBJEE)
2010	Offered Merit Scholarship (Top 50 in State	Higher Secondary Exam
2009	out of nearly 6,00,000 students). Certificate of merit for being placed in Statewise Top 1% and 10% at +2 level in	National Standard Exam
2008	Physics and Astronomy. Rank 5 in Kharagpur Sub-division and Honore "Academic Distinction" for securing 100% ma	•

Mathematics and 99% in Physical Science.

# **Arnab Mondal**

MS | IIT KGP || Software Eng. | LISTER || BE | IIESTS

# Hard Skills

#### Programming:

Arduino, Modelica	•	•	•	•	•	
Python, C, HTML(5)	•	•	•	•	•	
Bootstrap Framework	•	•	•	•	•	
CSS(3), JSON, SQL	•	•	•	•	•	
JQuery, Javascript	•	•	•	•		
Angular JS	•	•	•	•		
Matlab, PHP	•	•	•			
XML, LESS, Ajax	•	•	•			
C++, SASS/SCSS	•	•				
Java, SCALA, VHDL	•					

#### Tools / Frameworks:

Arduino IDE, Latex	••••
OpenModelica 1.1x.x	••••
MS Office, Sublime	••••
Magento (EE 1.14.x)	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet$
MATLAB, Simulink	••••
XAMPP / LAMP	• • • • •
Jira, Git, Eclipse	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ \circ$
Qt, NetBeans7	• • • • •
PSCAD (v4.x)	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ \circ$
BigCommerce	• • • • •
Oracle Maxymiser	$\bullet \bullet \circ \circ \circ$
Swing (Java)	$\bullet \bullet \circ \circ \circ$
Salesforce, Maxima	• • • • •
LabVIEW, SCADA	• • • • •

#### Hardwares:

NRF24L01+	•	•	•	•	•	
RIGOL DS1102E	•	•	•	•	•	
Arduino UNO & MEGA	•	•	•	•		
LoRa SX 12xx	•	•	•	•		
OPAL-RT OP4510	•	•	•			
PMU	•	•				

## Languages

- Bengali (Mother tongue)
- English (Professional & Daily use)
- Hindi (Survivable)

#### **Publications**

Ghosh and Mondal, et al.

36th ACM/SIGAPP Symposium on Applied Computing (SAC '21)

Jul 2020 A Programmable Open Architecture Testbed for CPS Education

Ghosh and Mondal, et al.

IEEE Design & Test (Volume: 37, Issue: 6, Dec. 2020)

## **Internships and Projects**

Aug 2014 – Analysis of Power System Networks for Optimal Placement of Phasor Measurement Units(PMUs)

Department of Electrical Engineering, IIEST Shibpur

Justified the proper placement of optimal no. of PMUs in a balanced section of the DVC GRID 220KV(Existing) to make the Smart Power

System Grid topologically observable.

Jun 2014 – Inflationary Universe From Einstein Gravity (Gravitation

Jul 2014 and Cosmology)

Manipal Centre for Natural Sciences(MCNS), Manipal University Worked on Friedmann-Lemaitre-Robertson-Walker (FLRW) Spacetimes for Flat Universe and explained inflationary universe from vaccum dominated stress-energy.

PPSP, WBSEDCL

Eden Garden, Kolkata

## **Vocational Trainings**

Dec 2013 –	Hydro-electric 900 MW power generation
Dec 2013 -	As <b>Trainee Operation Engineer</b>

Jan 2014 Closely monitored Pump Storage Hydro 900 MW power generation, underground Power House, SCADA (Supervisory Control And Data

Acquisition), 400kV GIS, and 132/33/11kV Substation.

Apr 2014 – Stadium services during Pepsi IPL 2014

Jun 2014

As Highmast Trainee Engineer

Monitored the lights (400V double-ended filament 2kW metal halide

lamps) which provide illumination of 2,500 lux (vertical) on the pitch, 2,000 lux in the 30-yard-circle and 1,500 lux across the outfield.

## **Positions of Responsibility**

Jul 2012 – Class and Placement Representative EE Dept., IIEST Shibpur

Apr 2015 Elected by 63 students of EE 2015 batch for ensuring good placements and coordination between administration and students.

Oct 2011 – University Photographer IIEST Shibpur

Jul 2015 Appointed to cover the IIEST Inaugural Ceremony, Convocation, annual Tochno Management Fost, and the annual Cultural Fost

nual Techno-Management Fest, and the annual Cultural Fest.

### **Extra-Curricular Activities**

Social and # Awarded Abritty VISHARAD in 2007-08 in Recitation securing 1st Class by Sarbabharatiya Sangeet-O-Sanskriti Parishad.

# Certificate of "Diploma in Guitar" by Shaw Academy in 2020.

# Member of Social and Cultural Committee in ATDC Department,

IIT Kharagpur since 2019.

# Member of IIT KGP photography club- "La Obscura" since 2019 and IIEST, Shibpur photography club- "CATHARSIS" since 2012.

Technical Won 1st and 2nd prize (out of nearly 30 teams) as a member of group of 5 in "JUNK-E WARS" event of INSTRUO 2012 and 2013.

Games and Represented VSRC Hall, IIT Kharagpur in inter-hall Cricket Tour-Sports nament in 2019-20; ATDC Department, IIT Kharagpur in inter-

June 15, 2021 Arnab Mondal

department RS Cricket Premier league in 2020.